准备好了吗  孩子们
Are you ready, kids?
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
我听不见
I can't hear you
好了船长
Aye aye, captain
是谁住在深海的大菠萝里
Who lives in a pineapple under the sea?
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
方方黄黄伸缩自如
Absorbent and yellow and porous is he
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
如果四处探险是你的愿望
If nautical nonsense be something you wish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
那就敲敲甲板让大鱼开路
Then drop on the deck and flop like a fish
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
准备
Ready
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob SquarePants
交友纪念日
编剧
翻译: 1440kHz
分镜总监
分镜指导
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
有人闯进来
Intruders
入室盗窃
A break-in
我就知道这罐发胶
I knew this can of hairspray
迟早会派上用场
would come in handy one day
谁在楼下
Who's down there?
我有发胶  而且我还敢拿它喷你脸
I have an aerosol can and I'm not afraid to use it
我的眼睛
My eyes
交友纪念
Happy friend-i
交友纪念日快乐
交友纪念日快乐  章鱼哥
Happy friend-iversary, Squidward
海绵宝宝  现在都几点了
SpongeBob, what time is it?
现在是我们相遇那天的
It's one minute after midnight
凌晨零点零一分
on the day that we first met
全都记在我的章鱼哥回忆录里了
It's all here in my Squidward memory book
章鱼哥
什么
What?
这张是我们参加夏令营
Here's us at camp
夏令营时光
这张是我搬到你隔壁
Here's when I moved in right next door
甜蜜的家
这张拍的是
And here's when I got
我又赢了你  当上了本月最佳员工
employee of the month instead of you again
这张是我几分钟以前拍的
Here's one I took a few minutes ago
看看你
Look at you
好像一个天使
Just like an angel
好了  给我得了
All right, that's it
滚出去
Get out
好
Okay
再见了  好朋友
see you around, friend
交到好朋友
Friend, friend, friend, friend, friend
交到一位好朋友
Friend, friend, friend, friend, friend, friend
交友纪念日
Friend, friend-iversary
交友纪念日快乐
Happy friend-iversary
还记得我第一次
Remember the first time
把你吓得摔进这个垃圾桶里吗
I startled you into this trash can?
走开
Go away
太经典了  章鱼哥
Classic, Squiddy
回忆
Memories
他在吗
Is he here?
不在
Not here
章鱼哥
Hey, Squidward
还记得我为你献歌的那一次吗
Remember that time I dedicated a song to you?
你还记得
You do remember
离我远点
Leave me be
还记得我给你买火箭轮滑鞋那次吗
Remember the time I got you these rocket skates?
不记得
No
因为现在这个就是全新回忆
That's because we're making a new memory
不
No
交友纪念日快乐
Happy friend-iversary
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
凯皮吉音乐会
The Kelpie G concert
这个回忆不错
Now, that was a good memory
还记得这个吗  章鱼哥
"Remember this, Squidward?"
还记得这个吗
章鱼哥
交友纪念日快乐
Happy friend-iversary
海草汽水
还记得这个吗  章鱼哥
Remember this, Squidward?
裤头村
还记得这个吗  章鱼哥
Remember this, Squidward?
求你一定要救救我
Please, you got to help me
还记得这个吗  章鱼哥
Remember this, Squidward?
不对
Oh, no
不要
No, no
交友纪念日
Friend-iversary
交友纪念日快乐
Happy friend-iversary
当晚
他全都记得
He remembers everything
一切发生过的事
Everything that happened
连没发生过的事都记得
Even things that didn't happen
以后会发生的事可能也记得
Maybe even things that will happen
不可能发生的事还能记得
Things that will never happen
凡是他记得的事都会发生
If he remembers it, it happens
一定要镇静  章鱼哥
Get ahold of yourself, Squidward
一定有办法能脱身
There's got to be a way out
一定有办法能消除
There's got to be a way to erase
橡皮擦
An eraser
我要擦掉他对我的回忆
I'll erase his memories of me
还有唯一一个存放回忆的地方
There's only one more place he keeps his memories
擦掉我
Erase me
章鱼哥  我们来当室友
Oh, Squidward, let's be roommates
一辈子住在一起到永远永远
and live together forever and ever and ever
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob?
早安
Good morning
你一定是新来的收银员吧
You must be the new cashier
很高兴认识你
Nice to meet you
真不敢相信
I can't believe it
成功了
It worked
我们先前见过吗
Have we met before?
没有吧
I don't think so
要不我们等会再聊
Maybe we can chat later, huh?
我现在有点忙
I'm kind of busy right now
今天是我一生最美好的一天
This is the best day of my life
你今天莫名高兴得有点怪了
You seem weirdly happy for some reason
怎么回事
What's going on?
昨晚
Last night
我消除了海绵宝宝对我的所有回忆
I erased all of SpongeBob's memories of me
是不是很棒啊
Isn't that wonderful?
你什么
You what?
你这是疯了吗
Are you insane, man?
为了避免痞老板扫描我意识
To keep Plankton from scanning me mind
只有海绵宝宝才知道
SpongeBob is the only one who knows
秘密配方保险箱的密码
the combination to the secret formula safe
由于海绵宝宝不想忘掉
And because he never wanted to forget it
他就把密码附在跟你一起的回忆之上
ha attached it to a memory he had with you
章鱼哥先生
Mr. Squidward
我要你马上复原他的回忆
I want you to un-erase his memory right now
海绵宝宝
SpongeBob
是的  蟹老板
Yes, Mr. Krabs
来跟章鱼哥先生共度下午时光
Spend the afternoon with Mr. Squidward here
他要跟你分享几个宝贵的回忆
He's gonna share some precious memories with you
不用了  谢谢
No, thank you
我不认识他
I don't know this guy
他是陌生人
He's a stranger
跟你说个悄悄话  感觉他有点无聊
Confidentially, he looks a little boring
你跟他一块走
You go with him
这是命令
That's an order
遵命
Yes, sir
那我们要干什么  新同事
So what are we doing now, new guy?
重新制造出你对我失去的回忆
We're going to recreate your lost memories of me
让你想起来蟹老板保险箱的密码
so you can remember the combination of Krabs' safe
一听就很扯  不过也行
Sounds crazy-pants, but okay
照我说的做
Just do what I tell you
泡泡
利马豆
好  要是这都没法让你想起我
All right, if this doesn't make you remember me
那就彻底没办法了
then nothing will
基本没什么印
Nope, it's just not ringing a
章鱼哥
Squidward
章鱼哥  我想起来了
Squidward, I remember this
我想起你了
I remember you
我想起保险箱的密码了
I remember the combination to the safe
万岁  万岁
Hooray, hooray
万岁
Hooray-ay-ay
那就太好了
Yeah, that's great
你别摇
Just stop shaking the
更烫的岩浆
密码是  向右三次撞击
The combination is three impacts to the right
不不不不
No, no, no, no
我的身子
My body
向左打五拳
Five punchings to the left
向右拉六肢
Six stretched limbs to the right
向左56个小学生
And 56 school children to the left
裤头村学校
不对  等下
No, wait
不是这个
That's not it
章鱼哥  我想起来了
Squidward, I remember
我想起来了
I remember
蟹堡王
跟你说  章鱼哥
You know, Squidward
我又想起一件事
there's something else I remembered
昨天不是我们的交友纪念日
Yesterday wasn't our friend-iversary
今天才是
It's today
不
No
不行
不要
No
交友纪念日快乐
Happy friend-iversary
还是明天来着
Or is it tomorrow?
强制音乐课
翻译: 1440kHz
编剧
分镜总监
指导总监
动画总监
统筹
监制
本字幕仅限学习交流
严禁用于商业用途
大家请注意
Attention, everyone
过来欣赏动听的免费音乐会
Gather round for a free concert of beautiful music
免费音乐会
A free concert
太好了
Fantastic
一  二
And a one, and a two
快带我走吧  查德
Get me out of here, Chad
冒犯到我耳朵了
My ears are offended
怎么回事
What's going on?
放我下来
Put me down
放开我的腿
Let go of my legs
我的竖笛
My clarinet
停
一群俗人
Philistines
健身房
再  来一遍
One, more time
不许动  先生
Freeze, mister
慢慢把竖笛放下来
Put the clarinet down nice and slow
你们算老几啊
Who are you supposed to be?
音乐警察吗
The music police?
说的没错
That's right, fella
你违反了
And you are in violation of
交响乐法典第四款
section four of the symphony code
违法
粗鲁吹奏簧鸣乐器
Reckless playing of a reed instrument
你的竖笛现已正式停用
Your clarinet is officially out of commission
什么
What the
如果你想要打开竖笛上的锁
If you want that boot off your clarinet
就必须去上强制音乐再教育课程
you'll have to undergo mandatory music reeducation
你开什么玩笑
You got to be kidding me
小脚蹼音乐学院
Little Flipper Music Academy
想得美
Oh, no
我才不上小屁孩才上的学校
I am not going to any school for minnows
不能就这样给我降级
You can't degrade me like this
对  大家都这么说
Yeah, that's what they all say
呼叫38号警卫
Calling Guard 38
有鼓手在比博普路的爵士俱乐部漏拍
a drummer missed a beat at the jazz club on Bebop Way
大家摇滚吧
Let's rock and roll
我绝对不可能坐在班级前排
I wouldn't be caught dead sitting in front of this class
坐在后面就看不到我了
They won't see me back here
同学们好
Good morning, class
请大家把椅子转过来
Would everyone please turn their chairs around?
好的  鲟老师
Yes, Ms. Sturgeon
什么
What?
可真是
For Neptune's sake
看样子今天有位新同学
It looks like we have a new student
就坐在我们前排
sitting right up front today
请你起立向全班自我介绍一下吧
Will you stand and introduce yourself to the class?
我的名字是章鱼哥
My name is Squidward Tentacles
我吹竖笛的年头
and I've been playing clarinet
比你们的年纪还要久
longer than you all have been alive
你为什么来这上课呢  章鱼哥先生
And why are you here, Mr. Tentacles?
法院命令我来的
Because of a court order
法院命令
Court order?
章鱼哥有法院命令
Squidward got a court order
住口
Stop it
同学们请安静
Now, settle down, class
很好
Oh, yes
我们今天还有一位新同学
We have one more new student joining us today
大家好
Hello
我是海绵宝宝
I'm SpongeBob SquarePants
我真的好期待
and I'm really looking forward to
章鱼哥  我都不知道你也来上这门课
Squidward, I didn't know you were taking this class too
也太美好了吧
Isn't this wonderful?
我们一起学音乐
We're musical classmates
杀了我吧
Kill me now
首先  请所有同学们
To begin, I would like each of you
演奏一下手上的乐器
to play your instrument
摸一下大家的底
to gauge everyone's skill level
所有同学一个一个来演奏
We'll go around the classroom one by one
费格斯  你先开始吧
Fergus, would you start us off?
很好  费格斯
Good effort, Fergus
内莉
Nellie
技巧挺有意思
Interesting technique
奥托  稍微弹一弹肩背式键盘吧
Otto, would you play a little on your key-tar?
进步空间很大
Definitely room for improvement
海绵宝宝同学
Student SquarePants
给大家鉴赏一下你的音乐才能吧
would you give us a taste of your musical talents?
可以
Certainly
鼻笛技术很棒  海绵宝宝先生
Excellent nose flute technique, Mr. SquarePants
现在有请章鱼哥先生
Now, it's time for Mr. Tentacles
向大家展示音乐才能
to demonstrate his musical abilities
我来向你们展示真正的做法
Now, let me show you how it's really done
加油  章鱼哥
Go, Squidward
打起精神
Brace yourselves
你们即将看到纯粹的天才之作
for you are about to witness a stroke of pure genius
听起来你确实有点东西
It did sound like you had some kind of stroke
竖笛对你这样的水平来说
The clarinet may be too
可能还是太过深奥了  章鱼哥先生
advanced for your level, Mr. Tentacles
也许你应该试试别的乐器
Perhaps you should try a different instrument
也许你应该多练练指法
Maybe you should just work on your fingering
给我得了
That's it
受不了你们闹来闹去了
I've had enough of this nonsense
拉响音乐警报
Must pull music alarm
音乐警报
章鱼哥
Squidward Tentacles
放下竖笛
put down the clarinet
避免伤害他人的耳膜
before someone's eardrums get hurt
过来拿啊  条子
Come and take it, copper
他力量太强大了
He's getting too powerful
该怎么办
What do we do now?
派遣指挥名家
Send in the maestro
闹够了吧  贝多粪
Fun's over, bad-toven
击掌
Up top
你再也没法用这个
You won't be hurting
伤害到任何人了
anyone with this anymore
你吹出邪恶颤音的日子结束了
Your villainous vibrato days are over
我再也演奏不出音乐了
I'll never play music again
没事的  章鱼哥
Don't worry, Squidward
可以培养新的爱好啊
You can take up a new hobby
比如说排绒毛或者拇指大战
Like lint sorting or competitive thumb twiddling
或者
Or
我压根没拇指
I don't have any thumbs
纸巾给你擤  兄弟
Go ahead and give it a big blow, buddy
那声音
That sound
好一个天籁
Positively angelic
继续擤  章鱼哥
Keep going, Squidward
你终于找到适合你的乐器了
You finally found your instrument
一直都近在眼前
It was right in front of your nose all along
其实就是你鼻子
In fact, it was your nose
不好意思
Excuse me
我想大家都能认可
I think we can all agree
章鱼哥先生是全班进步最大的同学
Mr. Tentacles is the most improved student in the class
太有才了
What a talent
再来
Encore
好样的  章鱼哥
Way to go, Squidward
再来
Encore